安静！
Quiet!
什么东西？
What are you?
你是恶魔！
You're a demon!
不 我不是 我不是恶魔
No, no. I'm not a demon.
我不是恶魔
I'm not a demon.
看见没？就是个人
See? Just a guy.
我只是来这里解救这些龙的人 所以我
Just a guy here to rescue these dragons, so, I.
- 但是你从火中走了出来！- 龙鳞而已！
- But you walked through fire! - Dragon scales!
龙经常蜕皮
Dragons shed a lot.
不 恶魔我可认得
No, I know a demon when I see one.
人的腿哪有这么细
No human legs are that skinny.
这出场方式不错吧？隆重登场
Think that's a good entrance? Get a load of me.
我就知道！不止一个恶魔！
I knew it! More demons!
他不过是一个
Ah, it's really just a nitwit.
忘了给屁股防火的傻瓜而已
who forgot to fireproof his butt.
烫 烫 太烫了！
Hot, hot, hot, hot!
伙计们 先别出手！
Guys, no, not yet!
- 看呀 你最恐怖的噩梦来临了 - 看呀
- Behold, your worst nightmare. - Behold.
和这位非要跟来的妹妹
Along with his sister, who insisted on coming.
你就这样介绍我？
That's my intro?
伙计们 太快了 你们总是来的太快了
Guys, too soon. You always come in too soon.
对不起 我还不太会控制我的翅膀
Sorry, still getting the hang of my wings.
鱼脚司 你又带宝宝来了？
Fishlegs, again with the baby?
- 这可是突袭 - 我找不到保姆
- This is a raid. - I couldn't find a sitter.
到处都是恶魔！
Demons everywhere!
世界末日来了
It's the end of the world!
亚丝翠 我都把他安排好了
Astrid. I had him right where I wanted him.
但是现在我已经把他安排好了
And now he's right where I wanted him.
我们开始干活吧
Let's get to work.
好吧 我们搞砸了开场
Okay, we screwed that up,
但是起码没有别人知道我们在这里
but at least nobody else knows we're here.
别紧张 姑娘 没事的
Easy, girl. It's okay.
我们是来放你出去的
We're gonna get you out of here.
是一头红角龙！
A Crimson Goregutter!
看看这家伙
Look at this weirdo.
我猜他蠢爆了
Bet it's super-dumb.
为什么我打不开这个笼子？
Why can't I get this cage open?
这是滑动门栓
It slides.
那可不
Obviously.
进攻！
Attack!
- 带这些龙出去！- 抓住那条夜煞！
- Get the rescues out of here! - Get that Night Fury!
别在甲板上跑！
No running on the deck!
甲板很滑 你会滑倒的
It's slippery. You could fall.
靠边站！让我来处理这个难缠的家伙
Step aside! Let me handle the tough guy stuff.
太好了！我打倒了两个
Yeah! That's two for me.
小心！
Look out!
- 不 不 不！- 对不起！
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no! - Sorry!
谢了
Thank you.
快去 伙计 放了剩下的那些
Now, go, get the rest, bud.
我以为这是一个秘密行动
I thought this was supposed to be a stealth mission.
可不 他们都爱这么大张旗鼓地开始
Yeah, they always start that way.
小心！
Look out!
谢了 风里飞！
Thanks, Stormfly!
别担心
Oh, stop worrying.
他们会处理好的
They'll get it.
终归会的
Eventually.
撤退！都救出来了
Move out! We got 'em all.
我要夹爆你们的头
I'm gonna headlock every last one of you.
我还要夹爆你的腿
I might even leg-lock you.
- 快走 快走！- 菜鸟们
- Let's go, let's go, let's go! - Amateurs.
- 我才刚刚开始 - 快走 伙计们！
- I was just getting started. - Clear out, guys!
快 快！
Go, go!
别让他们跑了！
Don't let them get away!
干得不错 伙计们！
Good hustle, boys!
无牙仔 该走了！
Toothless, time to go!
嗨 伙计们
Hey, guys.
你总能救我于水火 兄弟
You always have my back, bud.
这就是伯克 你们以后的新家
This is Berk, your new home away from home.
为你们提供绝妙
A stunning, one-stop,
一站式免费服务的梦想之地
all-expense-paid dream destination.
所以 安定下来 让你的忧虑烟消云散
So, settle in and let your worries melt away.
这里的服务质量在不断提升 菜品火爆
The service here soars, the cuisine is fiery.
当地龙和你们一样有趣
and the locals are as colorful as you get.
普通的天堂乐园都有沙滩和阳光
Any run-of-the-mill paradise boasts beaches and sunshine.
但是 我们可不是这样
Well, not us.
我们有别人接触不到的东西
We've got something no one else can touch.
- 我们 朋友们 我们有龙 - 让出点空间！
- We, my friends, have dragons. - Make room!
他们来了！
They're coming!
很多很多的龙
Lots and lots of dragons.
伙计们 见咱们见伯克的新成员
Gang, meet our latest Berkians.
欢迎来到天堂 老兄
Welcome to paradise, mate.
- 我们的家就是你的家 - 你真是个美人
- Our home is your home. - Well, aren't you a beauty!
不用客气 不用夸奖
Ah, you're welcome. You're welcome.
我打倒大概有一百个猎龙人
I took on, like, a hundred trappers.
不对是一千个
A-a thousand trappers.
全程穿着烧着的内裤
All with burning undies.
我浓密的络腮胡差点就烧着了
My thick full beard almost caught on fire.
停下来吧
Ugh. Just-just stop.
所以 小嗝嗝的妈妈
So, uh, Hiccup's mom,
有注意到我碎骨的一击吗
any notes on my bone-crushing assault,
是不是非常完美？
or was it pretty much perfect?
真是难以描述
Oh, it was indescribable.
还有 请叫我沃尔卡 我来这里有一年了
And please, call me Valka. It has been a year.
熟人成就达成
First-name basis.
我认为今天真正的英雄是无牙仔
I think the real hero of the day was Toothless.
对不对 兄弟？
Isn't that right, bud?
如果没有你我们可怎么办呀 龙王？
What would we do without you, oh, king of dragons?
可怎么办呀？
What would we do?
举例来说 我们可以加大训练量
Well, we could train a lot harder, for one.
大家太懒散了
That was pretty sloppy.
亚丝翠 说的没错
Astrid, uh, does have a point.
也许大家都有点太依赖龙了
Perhaps you all rely a little bit too much on your dragons.
而不是依赖彼此
and not enough on one another.
看见没？这就是我想说的
See? That's exactly what I was saying.
听听吧 伙计们
Just listen up, guys.
没错 你妈妈对我印象超好
Yeah, your mom's super impressed with me.
我就是她一直想要的儿子
I'm like the son she always wanted.
小鱼仔啊
Fishmeat.
你认识了新朋友
You found a new friend.
低头！
Mind your heads!
如果龙王不能维持秩序
What good is having the king of dragons around.
那么留着他什么用？
if he can't keep the order?
嘿 兄弟 你能管管吗 还是… ？
Hey, bud, do you want to do something here or…?
还有你想我们把他们安置在哪里？
And where do you suppose we put these ones?
我们会腾出空间的
Ah, we'll make room.
你们带回来一只贪噬龙！
You brought back a Hobgobbler!
他们是不祥之兆 我们被诅咒了
They're a bad omen. We're cursed.
胡说
Nonsense.
他能有什么伤害？
What harm could he do?
没有受伤
No injuries.
他们有点吓坏了 但身体都很健康
They're all a little shaken but otherwise healthy.
饿了吗？
Now, who's hungry?
重点是你不能总是不停把龙带回来
Point is you can't keep bringing dragons back here.
来啊 兄弟
Come on, boy.
你就是在自找麻烦
You're just asking for trouble.
不 你别跑 你这个小贼！
No, you don't, you little thief!
那些猎龙人一天天的离我们越来越近了
Those trappers are getting closer by the day.
能搞定的 我们有头龙呢
We can handle them. We have the alpha.
是不是 兄弟？
Ain't that right, bud?
你看他们多开心？
Would you look at how happy they are?
她太帅了
She's awesome.
戈伯 放轻松 我们办到了
Gobber, relax. We did it.
世界上第一个龙和维京人的乌托邦
The world's first dragon-Viking utopia.
我们让梦想照进了现实
We made the dream a reality.
也许那是你的梦想 我的梦想可没这么拥挤 而且
Your dream maybe. Mine's less crowded and more.
更卫生
sanitary.
戈伯 别自欺欺人
Gobber, you're not fooling anybody.
我知道的 你爱他们
I know you love them.
你们应该是带领我们
You're supposed to be the generation.
走向未来的一代人
that leads us into the future.
食物大战！
Food fight!
美极了
Ooh, gorgeous.
- 小心我的发型！- 乖小鱼仔
- Watch the hair! - Good, Fishmeat.
- 老天啊 - 直中眉心！
- Ugh! God help us. - Right between the eyes!
别担心外部问题了…
Time to stop worrying about problems out there…
- 戈伯 - 是时候处理下眼下的事情了
- Gobber. - and start sorting out the ones right here.
好 好
Okay, okay.
我… 我会考虑的
I. … I'll think about it.
别总骑着龙到处飞了 结婚吧
Hang up those saddles and get married.
结婚
The "M" word.
恶心 除非我结婚
Gross. Unless it's me.
是时候像正经皇室夫妇一样统治这片土地
Start ruling like a proper royal couple.
请 嫁给他
Marry him, please.
你是这里唯一明事理的人
You're the only one with any sense around here.
你来当家 就还有希望
With you wearing the pants, there's still hope.
戈伯啊
Gobber.
真是一点也不尴尬
Not awkward at all.
亚丝翠 别这样
Astrid, don't be like that.
明确的拒绝啊
Whoa. That is a definitive no.
听着 如果你需要胡须来擦鼻涕眼泪
Look, if you need a beard to cry on,
就靠在我的肩膀上 把眼泪流进
just lean on my shoulder and you can cry into.
我浓密的络腮胡里吧
my full, thick beard.
谢谢你 特夫纳特
Oh, thank you, Tuffnut.
谢谢
Thank you.
太感谢了
So much.
埃雷 埃雷之子！
Eret, son of Eret!
什么消息？
What's the report?
海峡里发现了猎龙人的两艘驳船
Two more trapper barges spotted in the strait.
我们去追他们
So we go after them.
- 什么？- 总有一天
- What? - One day,
你会挑起你赢不了的战役
you're gonna pick a fight you can't win.
弓箭手！
Archers!
- 屠龙人 - 保持警惕
- Dragon killers. - Stay on your guard.
毒钳
Deathgrippers.
后退！按我说的做！
Back! Do what I say, now!
按我说的做！
Do what I say!
抓住拉链的另一头！
Grab the other head on that Zippleback!
你属于…
You belong to the…
龙骑士是在这里袭击我们的
The dragon riders attacked us here,
就在东海峡一带
off the Eastern Strait.
- 雷戈纳 - 抱歉
- Ragnar. - Um, sorry.
我亲爱的军阀们
My dear warlords.
你们征服世界的计划怎么样了？
How go your plans to conquer the world?
葛林魔 我的老朋友
Grimmel, my old friend.
谢谢你能来
Thank you for coming.
据我了解 卓戈战败后有一年
A year since Drago's defeat,
没有和你们龙军合作了
and no further along with your dragon army, I see.
这都归功于伯克年轻的酋长
You can thank the young chief of Berk for that.
斯多戈的儿子？
Stoick's boy?
没错 他和他热爱和平的龙骑士们
Yep, he and his peace-loving dragon riders.
不断地袭击我们的船 还偷走了我们的龙
continue to raid our ships and steal our dragons.
听起来确实像是个烦人的家伙
Mm. That does sound like a nuisance.
但我做的是杀龙的生意
But I'm in the business of killing dragons,
没空去找龙
not retrieving them.
- 但是 葛林魔… - 那个小蠢货
- But, Grimmel… - That idiot boy has done.
已经帮你把事情都做好了
all of the work for you,
他把龙都聚集到了一个地方
gathering the dragons in one place.
又何必来烦我？
Why bother me?
因为有一只夜煞守卫着龙群
Because the flock is protected by a Night Fury.
不可能
Not possible.
看来有一只逃出了你的手掌心
It seems one slipped through your fingers.
伯克的龙群都听从头龙指挥
Look, Berk's dragons will follow the alpha.
我们付钱给你去抓他 把龙群引过来
So we'll pay you to capture him and bring the flock to us.
我们可有你最喜欢的诱饵
We even have your favorite bait.
昨晚袭击后 他们落下的唯一一条龙
The only dragon they left us from last night's raid.
一条雌的？
A female? Hmm.
那么 就这么说定了 老伙计？
So, do we have a deal, old friend?
小心！
Watch out!
到时候
When all is said and done,
这位年轻的族长会把夜煞给我送过来
this young chief will bring me the Night Fury.
他们没有首领 只有一个孩子
They don't have a leader, just a boy.
小嗝嗝
Hiccup.
这是伯克 孩子
This is Berk, son.
我们的家园
It's our home.
这是你的祖辈
It was the home of your grandparents.
和祖辈的祖辈生活的家园
and their grandparents before them.
作为首领 我的职责是保护族人 小嗝嗝
And it's my job as chief to protect us, Hiccup.
将来某天 等你长大成人
And one day, when you're all grown up,
这份职责将落到你身上
that job will be passed on to you.
好啊
Okay.
这很重要 儿子 因为那边
And it's very important, son, because out there,
落日的那头 是龙族的家园
beyond the sunset, lies the home of the dragons.
- 哇 - 是啊
- Wow. - Aye.
传言靠得太近的船只
Legends tell of ships that sailed too close to it,
会从世界的边缘坠下
only to drop off the edge of the world,
永远消失
never to be seen again.
但那些返航的水手说
But those sailors who turned back.
那里有一川大瀑布
told tales of a great waterfall.
龙族守卫着隐秘之地的入口
and dragons guarding the entrance to a Hidden World.
- 哇 - 那里不只是一处巢穴 小嗝嗝
- Whoa. - Not just a nest, Hiccup,
那是龙族的起源之地
but a land from which all dragons come.
夜煞也从那里来吗？
Even Night Furies?
特别是夜煞们
Especially Night Furies.
他们很可怕
Those are scary.
你不用担心
Don't you worry.
总有一天 我会找到隐秘之地
One day, I'll find the Hidden World.
并将它封闭
and seal it up,
人族和龙族间就不会再有战争
so that people and dragons will fight no more.
怎么了？
What?
好吧
Oh, all right.
你知道这不是咬着玩的东西 对吧？
You do know it's not a chew toy, don't you?
你想玩吗？你想要这条腿吗？
Is this what you want? Oh, do you want this leg?
你想要我的腿？那就接好
Do you want my leg? Go get it.
自己滑翔得很不错嘛 伙计
Getting pretty good at gliding on your own, bud.
所以你就是来这里躲着戈伯
Oh, so this is where you come to get away from Gobber.
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
他是对的 你要知道
Well, he's right, you know.
真的吗？
R-Really?
你觉得我们应该… ？
You think you and I should…?
老天 不是说那个
Oh, gods, no.
我们还没有准备好
We're nowhere near ready for that.
是 确实有点夸张
No, that's-that's crazy.
我是说 关于这些他是对的
I mean, he's right about all of this.
现在好像全世界都知道我们了
It does seem like the whole world knows about us now.
是啊 我们带回的龙越多
Yep. And the more dragons we bring back here,
就会成为更大的攻击目标
the bigger of a target we become.
我真希望我们可以不受人打扰
I just wish there was some way to make them leave us alone.
有办法的
There might be.
爸爸跟我讲过一个水手间流传的故事
Dad used to talk about an old mariners' myth,
在世界的边缘有一处无人抵达的秘境
of a secret land at the edge of the world.
龙族都在那里生活
where dragons live totally out of reach.
水手们出了名地爱讲荒诞故事
Well, sailors are known for tall tales.
确实 但如果是真的呢？
True. But what if it's real?
我们所有的问题都会迎刃而解
It could be the answer to all of our problems.
怎么做？要把龙群都迁到那里吗？
How? By moving the dragons there?
我们都迁过去
Uh-uh. All of us.
认真的吗？
Seriously?
就这样抛弃我们生活了七代的家园？
And abandon our home of seven generations?
这片你父亲留给你守护的家园
The home your father left you to protect.
我认为我们需要一个切实的办法 小嗝嗝
Yeah, I think we need a real solution, Hiccup.
我们可以听戈伯的建议
Well, we could just take Gobber's advice.
缔结连理
and tie the knot.
这样所有问题都解决了
That should fix everything.
但是 如果你对在下还有什么不称心的地方
But, hey, if you're having doubts about yours truly,
鼻涕虫可还是单身呢
I'm pretty sure Snotlout's available.
他眼里只有你妈妈
He only has eyes for your mom.
- 耍招数呢？- 是你先招惹我的
- Playing dirty now, huh? - You asked for it.
看来总要举办一场婚礼了
Looks like there might be a wedding after all.
你好大胆 这么龌蹉
Oh, how dare you? That is a low blow.
不 你跑不掉的
No, no, you are not getting away.
好吧 好吧 你赢了 你赢了！
Okay, okay, you win, you win!
总是你赢
You always win.
你早知道会是这个下场
You knew what you were getting into.
行吧
Uh-huh. Right.
伙计？
Uh, bud?
什么… 当然 不用费心等我们
What… Yeah, sure, don't bother to wait for us.
我的天啊
Oh, my gods.
小嗝嗝！
Uh, Hiccup!
对 对 我们是朋友 没必要杀我们
Yeah, yeah, w-we're friends. No need to kill us.
- 哇 - 另一只夜煞
- Wow. - Another Night Fury.
不 也不是 倒像一只…
No, not quite. It's more like a…
- 亮… 煞 - 一只光煞
- Bright… Fury. - A Light Fury.
你的更恰当一点
Yeah, yours is better, probably.
你说消失是什么意思？
What do you mean, gone?
凭空就不见了
Vanished, into thin air.
- 你看怎么样？- 不对
- What do you think? - Uh-uh.
耳朵要短一些 没有背甲
Stubbier ears. No dorsal plates.
好 知道了
Okay. Got it.
这一晚上真够忙活
What a night.
伙计 你这是怎么了？
Bud, what's gotten into you?
又流口水又喘气？
What is all this slobbering and panting?
这还不明显吗？他恋爱了
Isn't it obvious? He's in love.
相信我 爱情只会带来痛苦和悲伤
Trust me, relationships are nothing but pain and misery.
我刚才说什么了？
What did I just say?
有我还不够吗？
A-Am I not enough?
看来是不太够
I think that's a no.
- 是这个样子吗？- 要不这样？
- Something like this? - You know what?
按无牙仔卡片临摹一张 换成白色的就行
Just trace your Toothless card and make her white.
- 早说不就好了 - 你敢信吗？
- You could've led with that. - Can you believe it?
无牙仔有女朋友了
Toothless has a girlfriend.
我不记得你是个爱浪漫的人
I never took you for a romantic.
从没觉得
Like, ever.
但这太甜了
But it's so sweet.
你看啊
I mean, look.
这太可悲了
Okay. That's just sad.
- 还有点怪异 - 你还是做点什么好
- And weird. - Yeah, you better do something.
说实话？我宁愿每天铲便便也不想看这个
Seriously? I'd rather shovel poop all day than watch that.
好吧 我们回头去树林
All right. Let's head back to the woods.
看能不能找到她
and see if we can find her.
好主意
Ah, good idea.
借一步说话
A little privacy.
- 男人间的谈话 - 什么？
- It's boy talk. - What?
走吧 我们谈一下这个
Come on, let's go work this out.
那么 你想结婚
So, you want to get married.
不 其实不想
Uh, no, actually.
好消息 我去过两次婚礼
Good news. I've been to two weddings.
都是不请自来 但是都没这次的规格高
I crashed both, but none as high profile as this one.
压力很大 还要担心别人的看法 不仅仅是我的
Lots of pressure, judgment, and not just by me.
我们谈过了 我们暂时不会结婚
Look, we talked about it. We're not getting married.
害怕了 这种情况我见过
Cold feet. I've seen it before.
别担心 小嗝子 有我在
Don't worry, Little Hiccy. I'm here.
等等 小嗝子？
Wait, Hiccy?
我知道亚丝翠是怎么看你的
Now, I've seen the way Astrid looks at you.
大家都是 有一些怀疑
Everyone has. That doubt.
那种有点强烈的失望
That not so subtle disappointment.
对你高高的期盼
That longing for something more than you.
你需要变得优秀
You need to focus on being worthy.
我是说 她是皇后又是个女战士
I mean, she's a warrior queen, for Thor's sake.
你却一样也不占
And you are neither.
但是我来做你伴郎…
But with me as your best man…
给你精神指引 如果你能…
your spirit guide, if you will…
你能重拾维京之魂
you'll learn to embrace your inner Viking.
给这些为数不少的反对者们看
Show these naysayers, of which there are many,
告诉他们 你才不是一头营养不良
that you're more than just a malnourished runt.
发质糟糕 长一口怪牙 脖子细弱的小家牛
with bad hair, strange teeth, and a twig for a neck.
你 你真不会聊天
You're-you're really bad at pep talks.
别让这些弱点
Stop letting these insecurities.
阻止你变得优秀
get the best of you.
大家都看着你呢 真的 每个人
Everyone's watching. I mean, everyone.
你要更男人一点 照我说的做
You need to man up. Do as I do.
虽然有点难 但我会帮助你
It'll be hard, but you have my word.
我不会放弃的 除非我食言
And until I break that word, I won't give up.
嘿
Hey.
嘿！怎么回事 我都白说了吗？
Hey! What, am I wasting my time here?
你在树林里看见什么发光的玩意儿… 这是啥？
You see some shiny thing in the woods… Ooh, what is that?
无牙仔！
Toothless!
不要动
Don't move a muscle.
嘿！
Hey!
- 有人来过了 - 哈？
- Someone's here. - Huh?
他绕过了我们的巡查
He managed to slip past our scouts.
在树林里设下了陷阱
and lay a trap in the woods.
把我们的谈话都毁了
It ruined boy talk.
- 我去抓他！- 慢着 戈伯
- Gah, let me at him! - Slow down, Gobber.
我们派一支队伍在地上搜查 空中再派人侦察
Let's get a search team on the ground, scouts in the air.
无牙仔和我巡查海岸
Toothless and I will fly the coastline.
我不建议带无牙仔出任务 酋长
Yeah, I wouldn't advise taking Toothless anywhere, Chief.
我认识这东西
I know this handiwork.
奸猾葛林魔 在我们那他很出名
Grimmel the Grisly. Famous back where I'm from.
是我见过的最狡猾的猎龙高手
The smartest dragon hunter I ever met.
当然 在我之下
Well, next to me, of course.
他也没那么聪明 他只留下一个没人管的陷阱
Well, he can't be that smart. He left his trap unmanned.
老葛林魔从来都是机关用尽 不露痕迹
Nothing's accidental when it comes to old Grimmel.
他以猎龙为生
He lives for the hunt,
能懂得猎物的想法
to get inside the mind of his prey,
控制他们的行动
to control its every choice.
对他来说 这不过是一场游戏
It's all a game to him.
他还不知道他惹上谁了
Well, he doesn't know who he's playing with.
是的 我们之前对付过他这种人
Yeah. Well, we've dealt with his kind before.
别小瞧他 小嗝嗝
Don't underestimate him, Hiccup.
记住我的话 他还会回来的
Mark my words. He'll be back.
那我们就等着他
Then we'll be waiting for him.
来吧
All right.
拜托 给我个线索
All right, come on, give me a clue here.
给我个提示 老爸
Give me a clue, Dad.
请你原谅我自便了
Oh, I hope you don't mind if I help myself.
这茶不错
This is, uh, mmm, quite good.
武器不错 但先让我喝完这杯茶
Oh, that is impressive. But let me finish my drink.
无牙仔！
Toothless!
你对他做了什么？
What did you do to him?
只是让他睡个好觉
Eh, nothing that he won't sleep off.
我可以坐下吗？
May I?
小嗝嗝酋长
Chief Hiccup.
我该叫你酋长呢还是小嗝嗝呢？
Hmm? Do I say Chief or do I call you Hiccup?
你喜欢哪一个？
What do you prefer?
你不知道我是谁 是吗？
You have no idea who I am, do you?
你父亲认识我
Well, your father knew of me.
他是一位伟大的酋长
Now, there was a chief.
也是有史以来最伟大的猎龙人之一
One of the greatest dragon hunters to have ever lived.
若他还在 又会如何看待你呢？
What would he think of you?
他做的没错
He had it right, you know.
担起了打败恶兽的重任
Making it his mission to destroy the beasts.
所以你才能在这个更好的世界里长大
so that you could grow up in a better world.
但他改变主意了
He changed his mind.
看看他最后的下场
And look where that got him.
我们还是说重点吧
So let's get to the point.
我是夜煞猎手
I am the Night Fury killer.
我已经杀了所有的夜煞 除了你那一条
I've hunted every last one but yours.
把他交给我 不然…
You are going to give me that dragon, or I will…
我绝对不会把他交给你的
I will never give him up.
你希望龙和人一样自由平等的生活在一起？
You wish dragons to live free among us like equals?
危险的想法 孩子
A toxic notion, my boy.
历史已经证明了我们才是最高贵的种族
History has shown that we are the superior species.
如果你这种错误的想法广为传播 后果该如何？
What if word of your misguided ideas were to spread?
人类文明将走上毁灭之路
It would be the undoing of civilization.
就如我们所知的
as we know it.
我们抓住他了吗？
Did we get him?
动手！
Now!
抱歉 我闯了进来
Sorry to barge in.
你觉得你可以就这样闯进我家
You think you can come into my home,
坐在我父亲的椅子上 威胁要抓我的龙？
sit in my father's chair, and threaten my dragon?
这里是伯克岛
This is Berk.
我们这一路来打败的坏蛋可比你厉害多了
And we have defended our way of life from far worse than you.
战斗精神 我喜欢
A fighting spirit. I love it.
但你好像犯了个错误
Only I'm afraid you're mistaken.
你说的那些坏蛋和我还差得远呢
You've never seen anything like me.
亚丝翠 小心！
Astrid, look out!
小心！孩子 躲开
Look out! Son, get clear.
快跑！
Run!
我下次来的时候
Have my dragon ready.
把我的夜煞准备好 不然我会毁掉你爱的一切
when I return, or I will destroy everything you love.
- 拿上水桶！- 怎么会发生这种事？！
- Grab the buckets! - How did this happen?!
- 进去 - 大半夜什么事
- Inside. - It's the middle of the night.
- 要我们来这干什么？- 好了
- What are we doing here? - All right.
好了 各位 稍安勿躁
All right, everybody. Settle down, please.
鱼脚司啊
Fishlegs.
你以前见过那个品种的龙吗？
Have you ever seen that species of dragon before?
让我来对付他！
Let me at him!
我会好好招待他的！
I'll give him a piece of my mind!
我是说 用拳头！
And by mind, I mean fist!
你是不是忘了我们差点就没命了？
Did you miss the part where we almost died?
你看到我的房子了吗？
Have you seen my house?
这是一个前所未有的强敌
This is a new kind of enemy.
是我小瞧了他 这是我的错
And I underestimated him. Now, that's on me.
但我不会再犯同样的错了
But I will not do that again.
我们是维京人 我们可不怕打架
We're Vikings. We don't run from a fight.
至少我不会 你倒是不一定
At least, I don't. You might.
我支持小嗝嗝
I agree with Hiccup.
葛林魔的手段可不止这些
We haven't seen the last of Grimmel.
他是猎龙人 固执又有耐心
He's a predator, single-minded and patient.
不得到猎物绝不罢休
He won't stop until he gets what he wants.
我同意埃雷的话
I'm with Eret.
我们必须谨慎对待这次危机
We have to take this threat seriously.
葛林魔只是反对势力的代表
Grimmel is just a sign of the times.
我们的敌人变得更聪明也更坚定了
Our enemies are getting smarter, more determined.
我们的岛不仅是越来越拥挤 还容易暴露 易受攻击
We're not just overcrowded. We are exposed and vulnerable.
全面开战对我们很不利 甚至要赌上所爱之人的性命
Short of full-blown war and risking everyone we love,
那我…
I don't…
我觉得继续留在这已经没有意义了
I don't see a way of staying here any longer.
如果斯多戈在世 他会怎么想？
What would Stoick think of this?
听他把话说完！
Hey! Hear him out!
如果大家想平静地和龙生活在一起
If we want to live in peace with our dragons,
我们需要一个更好的计划
we need a better plan.
你到底想说什么 酋长？
So what are you saying, Chief?
我是说我们该消失了
I'm saying we have to disappear.
从这地图上消失
Off the map.
带着龙去一个谁也找不到的地方
Take the dragons to a place where no one will find them.
那会在哪呢？
And where might that be?
他说的是隐秘之地
He's talking about a quest for the Hidden World.
隐秘什么？
The hidden what?
- 疯了吧 - 是啊
- Out to lunch. - Yeah.
我小的时候我父亲就一直有这个想法
My father was obsessed with it when I was a boy.
在寻找龙族起源地的时候
He made notes and maps.
他留下了笔记和地图
in search of the ancestral home of all dragons,
隐秘之地就在世界边缘的某处
tucked away somewhere beyond the edge of the world. The Hidden World.
它也许是我们需要的解决方案
It may be the solution we need.
我们是驯龙人
We are dragon people.
我们属于那个地方
It's where we belong.
听着 我知道这里是我们的家
Look, I know this is our home.
我的父亲让我留下保护这里
My father left me to protect it.
但伯克不止是一个地方
But Berk is more than this place.
我们就是伯克
We are Berk.
人类 龙族
The people, the dragons.
我们在哪 那里就是伯克
I say Berk is wherever we go.
我不知道
I don't know.
你怎么看？
What do you think?
我支持他！还有谁？！
I'm with him! Who else?!
不好意思 借过一下
Excuse me. Coming through.
让我过去一下
Just, let me just get right through here.
小鱼仔 看 吃小石头 吃石头
Fishmeat, look, eat your rocks. Eat your rocks.
天啊 带着孩子飞的人最糟糕了
Gods! People who fly with babies are the worst.
我感觉我一直在问你这个问题 但是…
I feel like I'm always asking you this question, but…
醒醒 格拉姆！醒醒
Wake up, Grump! Wake up!
你是真的有计划还是… ？
Is there an actual plan or…?
一直往前飞到世界的尽头
Just keep flying until we reach the end of the world.
听起来有点道理
Ah. Seems sensible.
他们在哪？
So, where are they?
很明显 走了
Gone. Obviously.
那只夜煞从你手里逃走了？
The Night Fury escaped you?
- 又逃走了？- 我故意放他们走的
- Again? - I encouraged it.
他们放弃了唯一的庇护所
They've abandoned their only defensible position.
仓皇而逃
Running scared.
只带了一丁点行李
with what little they can carry.
怎么还没到头啊
It just keeps going.
那是因为这世界是圆的
That's 'cause the world is actually round.
太阳是圆的 月亮是圆的
The sun's round. The moon is round.
星星是圆的
Stars are round.
虽然他们看起来又小又笨
Even though they're small and stupid.
对吧？星星
Right? Stars.
别担心 他们跑不远的
Don't fret. They won't get far.
那条夜煞心烦意乱
The Night Fury is distracted.
我把他介绍给你们的小母龙了
I introduced him to your female.
夜煞对伴侣都忠贞不渝
Furies mate for life, you see.
你发现什么了 兄弟？
What you picking up on, bud?
那条光煞！
The Light Fury!
她一直跟着我们！
She's following us!
酷
Cool.
- 你看到了吗？- 她去哪了？
- Would ya look at that? - Where'd she go?
慢点 无牙仔！
Whoa! Hold up, Toothless!
看看那是谁啊
Well, look who it is.
很高兴 我们终于…
Oh, hey, it's really nice to finally…
真带劲
This is perfect. So great.
闭嘴
Not a word.
好吧好吧 他们到底去哪了？
Y-Yes, yes, but where did they go?
我得解释一下
I have to explain this.
夜煞不能抵御寒冷
Night Furies can't survive in the cold,
所以肯定不是北方
so they haven't gone north.
他们要离敌人越远越好
They're trying to put distance between themselves.
而敌人在东方
and enemies to the east.
和南方
and south.
夜煞不能不休息地
And Night Furies cannot fly.
长途飞行
long distances without rest.
所以中途必须找地方休息
Their flight path must include stops.
休息一下！
Potty break!
因此 他们去了…
Therefore, they've gone…
也只能去…
They can only have gone…
有人想猜一下吗？
Does anyone want to take a guess?
有吗？
Anyone?
夕… 希…
W-W. … W-W-W…
啊 东方！
Ah, east!
西方
West.
就是这么简单 看到吗？
Hmm? Simple, you see?
是不是很好玩？
Oh, isn't this fun?
好玩吧？不好玩？
Yes? No?
好玩 好玩
Yes. Yes.
你们对猎龙的热爱呢？
Where is your love of the hunt?
你们不是征服者吗？
I thought you were conquerors.
你们一定会收获颇丰的
You'll have your prize in time.
就让我再多享受几天吧
Just allow me a few more days to enjoy this.
我很怀念这种感觉呢
I have dearly missed it.
好吧
All right.
看来我们今晚要在这儿扎营了
Looks like we're camping here for tonight.
太好了 真是谢天谢地
Well, thank Thor for that.
是的 我的地盘
Yes. My own place.
我要造个小屋 只给有胡子的人住
I plan to build a hut, only for the bearded.
拉芙纳特 你得呆在外面
Ruffnut, you got to stay out.
下巴上长的胡子不能算
Chin whiskers don't count.
我看到了我体内的男子气概
I see a tower of manliness in the shape of me.
比埃雷还高 肌肉也比他强壮
It's gonna be taller than Eret with bigger muscles.
什么？
W-What?
滚出我的房子！
Get out of my house!
- 我们之间有梁子吗？- 对 有梁子
- Is there a problem here? - Yeah, there's a problem.
自从你出现之后
Ever since you showed up,
就一直抢我的风头
you've been trying to upstage me.
你嫉妒心太强了 别妄想了
You're just so jealous. It's delusional.
对 妄想这个词很恰当
Yeah, delusion's a good word for it.
听着 埃雷之子
Listen, son of Eret.
小嗝嗝是酋长 我就是他的接班人
When Hiccup blows it as chief, I'm next in line.
二当家 因为沃尔卡最喜欢我
Number two, 'cause I'm clearly Valka's favorite.
所以 你最好现在开始对我放尊重点
So, you better start showing me some respect.
奇怪的小矮子
Strange little man.
不用搭理他
Ah, don't mind him.
拥有神祗般完美的身材又不是你的错
It's not your fault you have the body of a Norse god.
我自己也有同样的困扰
I myself have the same problem.
这地方是我的
This one's mine.
铁匠铺就选在这儿了
Blacksmith's stall goes right here.
一 二 三 四 五
One, two, three, four, five.
什么… ？
What's…?
大家等一下 我… 说的是扎营
Uh, hold on, gang. I. … I said make camp.
- 你看到他们了吗？- 不是造个新镇子
- Did you see them? - Not build a new village.
谁升了天 让你当了酋长？
Who died and made you chief?
干嘛？疼！
What? Ow!
自然 这地方非常不错
Granted, this place is very nice,
但并不是隐秘之地
but it's not the Hidden World.
我们都不知道它存不存在
We don't even know if this Hidden World exists.
没错 这地方却是实实在在的
Yeah. This place is real.
没有什么人能比一群
Eh, there's nothing more stubborn.
又累又饿的维京人更固执
than a mob of tired, hungry Vikings.
我想我们可以暂时把这里当做基地
Well, I guess this can work as a base in the meantime.
这里利于防守 也很隐秘
It's defensible, hidden.
好吧 你们可以留下
All right. You can stay.
和新伯克打声招呼！
Say hello to New Berk!
大家动手造起来
Let's get building, lads.
等我和无牙仔找到隐秘之地就走
Until Toothless and I find the Hidden World.
别再瞎想了！
Get off it!
话说你的声音
Now, about that voice.
能不能别说话像鹅叫一样吗？
Can we lose the whole honking goose thing?
如果你婚礼上面时不时发出鹅叫声
It's hard to imagine wedded bliss.
那可是有好戏看了
with that going off every minute.
如果你还要继续向西
If you're going to continue west,
我应该往回巡逻一下 以防被跟踪
I should head back to make sure we weren't followed.
好主意 我和你一起去 保护你
Great idea. I'll go with you for protection.
不用！你留在这里比较重要
No! You're far too important here.
对啊
Yeah.
小心点
Just be careful.
看看这地方！太棒了！
Look at this place! It's amazing!
- 那块石头不错 - 怎么了？
- That's a nice rock. - What?
这个让我们隐藏起来的计划
This plan to hide us from the rest of the world.
虽然… 虽然我真心希望它可行
Though… though I wish it were possible,
我怕会撑不了多久 小嗝嗝
I fear it can't last, Hiccup.
我是说这么多年来 我也在努力做同样的事
I mean, you know I tried to do the same for years.
可贪婪的人类总能钻到空子
But greedy humans always find a way.
我只是… 只是想让你再深思熟虑一下
I just… I only ask that you think about it.
这是我的
This one's mine.
是我先把斧子扎在这里的
I threw my axe down first.
你还觉得我太疯狂了吗… ？
Do you still think I'm crazy or…?
要我说 这整个计划很有你的风格
Let's just say this whole idea is very you.
谢谢你昨晚支持我
Well, thanks for supporting me last night.
这对我意义重大
It meant a lot.
先别急着谢我
Don't thank me yet.
我只希望你的计划是对的
I just hope you're right about this.
- 我喜欢这里 - 我一直很想要个能看日落的地方
- I like it here. - I always wanted a sunset view.
无牙仔 别吵 现在太早了
Toothless. No, it's too early.
现在你倒是会画画了
Oh, now you can draw.
- 看来你根本没睡呀 - 没错
- Oh. Someone hasn't slept. - Yeah.
那只光煞不会让我靠近到一英里以内
Well, that Light Fury won't let me within a mile of her.
在无牙仔泡上妞之前 我俩都没法睡
And neither of us will be getting any sleep.
更别提去找什么隐秘之地了
or finding the Hidden World until Toothless takes over.
嘿！
Hey!
你觉得这个怎么样？
What do you think of that?
没错
Yeah.
你之前也试过一次 但他不想要
You tried this once before. He didn't want it.
那是因为以前他没有特殊的理由
Well, until now, he didn't have a reason to.
对吧 哥们？
Right, bud?
怎么了？
What?
没什么 我只是很欣慰
No, nothing. I'm… I'm impressed.
看看你 竟然愿意接受改变了
I mean, look at you. Embracing change.
我很为你自豪
I am proud of you.
他是我最好的哥们
Well, he's my best bud.
我想让他开心
I want him to be happy.
而且等他把妞带回来 就不需要这个了
Eh, besides, it's just until he brings her back.
好了
All right.
- 发个火球 - 哦！
- Fire when ready. - Oh!
你大概早知道那尾巴是防火的了
Well, I guess you know the tail is fireproof.
好了 无牙仔
Okay, Toothless.
好了好了 别闹 我知道了
Okay, okay. Okay, yes, I know.
我知道了
I know.
Okay, I know.
- 别动 不然我装不好 - 看看 看看
- Please, this is not helping. - Well, well, well.
他好兴奋呀
Someone's excited.
他刚经历了第一次约会
He's fresh off his first date.
现在他眼里只有爱情了
Now he's love crazed.
留我们在这里发疯
Only we're the ones going crazy.
他越快能把光煞带回来越好
The sooner he brings back that Light Fury, the better.
要想带她回来 他得单独飞行才行
Yeah, but to do that, he'll need to fly without me.
所以是时候试试这个改良版的新玩意了
So time to give this new and improved baby a shot.
真棒 你看上去帅极了 无牙仔！
Attaboy. Looking sharp, Toothless!
你觉得怎么样 哥们？
So what do you think, bud?
带她回来
Bring her home.
得在太阳下山前回来
By sundown at the latest.
别闹 精力留给你女朋友吧
No, save it for your girlfriend.
走吧 赶紧去吧
Go on. Get out of here.
没事的
It's okay.
小心！
Watch out!
走 云中跃！
Go, Cloudjumper!
敬酋长！
To the chief!
没错 敬酋长
Aye. To our chief.
你真是你父亲的翻版
Oh, a chip off the old block.
别抛了 各位 我感觉有点想吐了
Yeah, okay, guys. Now I'm just getting sick.
好了
Okay.
我得说
Got to say,
我之前还以为你是在瞎胡闹
I thought you were well off your rocker,
但这地方还是不赖的
but this spot ain't half bad.
这里只是一个暂时的基地
This was supposed to be a temporary solution.
大家都没异议
It's unanimous.
大家都觉得这地方比原先的更棒
Everyone agrees we've definitely traded up.
干得好 酋长
Well done, Chief.
万一尾巴坏了怎么办？
What if the tail broke?
万一葛林魔找到他了呢？
What if Grimmel found him?
- 万一他需要我呢？- 放轻松 好吗？
- What if he needs me? - Would you relax?
也许他就是在享受龙生最美好的时刻
He's probably having the time of his life.
我怎么知道？她从来不接近我们
How would I know? She never comes around.
每次来了 也都会匆匆飞走
And when she does, she's always rushing off.
我是想说… 我们怎么知道
I'm saying how… how do we know.
她适合和我们一起住呢？
if she's right for us?
- 我们？- 你懂我的意思吧
- Us? - You know what I mean.
她太野性也太狡猾 这么说吧
She's so wild and skittish. I'm just gonna say it.
我不信任她
I don't trust her.
你没法驯服所有龙 小嗝嗝
Can't tame 'em all, Hiccup.
总有一天 你得把那些牵绊都给剪断
One day, you'll have to snip those apron strings.
让无牙仔自己翱翔
and let Toothless stretch his wings.
这让我想起了我和斯多戈上次聊你的时候说的话
Reminds me of a talk I had with Stoick about you.
他们是从哪里来的？
Where do they keep coming from?
- 谁？- 那些可怕的贪噬龙
- Who? - Those bloody Hobgobblers.
我敢打赌他们比兔子生得还要快
I swear they're popping up faster than rabbits.
我觉得他们是想吃了我
I think they want to eat me.
肯定有证据显示我很好吃
Evidence would suggest I'm tasty.
小嗝子 你有空吗？
Hiccy, a moment?
听着 我一直在观察你的走路姿势
Listen, I've been watching you walk.
别一瘸一拐的 新娘不会喜欢
Lose the limp. No one's gonna marry that.
可我这条是假腿
I have a prosthetic leg.
- 我的也是 - 我还有个寄生双胞胎呢
- So have I. - And I have a parasitic twin,
可你也没见我一瘸一拐到处走吧
but you don't see me limping around about it.
来吧 抬头 小嗝子 挺胸
Come on. Chin up, Hiccy. Puff out that chest.
胯往左边再多摆一些
Move that butt to the left a little bit.
妈 你受伤了？外面出什么事了？
Mom, are you hurt? W. … What happened out there?
我不知道葛林魔用了什么办法 但他在跟踪我们
I don't know how, but Grimmel is tracking us.
啊！这一切肯定都是贪噬龙的锅
Ah! This is all because of the Hobgobblers.
他有一百艘船 可能更多
He has a hundred ships, maybe more,
还有足够装下我们这些龙的笼子
with enough cages for all of our dragons.
如果葛林魔带船队来这里
If Grimmel is leading them here,
我们必须要干掉他
we have to take him out of the mix.
我们要怎么干掉他呢？
Uh, and how would we do that?
去船上抓他
By going there to capture him.
抓他？
Capture him?
我加入！还有人来吗？！
I'm with him! Who else?!
好了 我们分开走 就不容易被抓到了
Okay, split up. We'll be harder to catch.
我觉得我们应该分开走 这是我的直觉
I was thinking we should split up, just because.
我喜欢你的直觉
I like your instincts.
什么情况？
What is this?
嘘！嘘！别出声
Shh! Shh! Quiet.
- 别出声 - 你需要你的龙的时候
- Quiet. - Where's your dragon.
他跑去哪儿了呢 酋长？
when you need him, hmm, Chief?
肯定是把你们都忘了吧
Must have forgotten all about you.
狩猎的第一要则：
First rule of the hunt:
把猎物从群落里引出去
Separate the prey from its pack.
你们刚才自动退出了这场游戏
You've just removed yourselves from the equation.
- 你为什么要这么做？- 你真要问这个？
- Why are you doing this? - Really?
我还以为你不在乎呢
I didn't think you cared.
和你不一样 我小的时候
Well, unlike you, when I was a boy.
遇到过一只夜煞 我趁它睡觉的时候杀了它
and I came upon a Night Fury, I killed it where it slept.
这勇气之举让我成为了村子的英雄
That simple act of courage made me a hero in my village.
所以我决定要杀光它们
So I decided to kill every last one,
为这个世界的人们带来真正的和平
bringing real peace to the people of this world.
直到你出现了
Until you came along,
到处宣扬那些龙不是小偷
preaching that dragons are something other than.
也不是杀人的动物
thieves and murderers.
这狗屁理论现在就要完蛋了 就从杀了你开始
That nonsense dies now, starting with you.
但你自己也有龙
But you have dragons of your own.
这些吗？
These?
他们是用来杀龙的
They're dragon killers,
他们自己的毒液让他们服从我的命令
drugged into obedience with their own venom.
连你那只宝贝头龙都没法控制他们
Not even your precious alpha could control them.
他们只只听命于我一个人
They serve me and only me.
我来示范给你们看
Allow me to demonstrate.
躲起来！
Take cover!
分开！
Split up!
快跑！
Run!
上来这里！
Up here!
快！
Hurry!
跑 跑 跑！
Go, go, go, go, go!
小嗝嗝！
Hiccup!
抓住你了
Gotcha.
走 云中跃！
Go, Cloudjumper!
棒呆！
Yeah!
我们的英雄！
Our hero!
他去哪儿都带着那只愚蠢的龙宝宝
Ugh, he takes that stupid baby everywhere.
谢天谢地！
God almighty!
我猜这个笼子是用不上了 是吧？
Guess we won't be needing this then, huh?
我带人正中了他的圈套
I led us right into his trap.
真是干得棒 酋长 对吧 拉芙？
Yeah, nice work, Chief. Right, Ruff?
等等
Wait.
- 呃… - 拉芙纳特在哪儿？
- Uh… - Where is Ruffnut?
我们… 没带上她吗？
We… we left her behind?
你怎么没发现她不见了呢？
How could you not notice she was missing?
你这龙另一只脑袋上没人呢
You ride a two-headed dragon.
好吧
Oh, yeah.
我觉得我和拉芙纳特一样蠢了
I feel like how Ruffnut is every day: dumb.
奥丁都要气跳脚了！
Odin be spanked!
这事情越来越乱了
This just gets better and better.
还有什么好消息吗？
Any more fantastic news?
我一般都尽量不去看她
I try to avoid looking at her.
不然会让我恶心反胃酸
It gives me acid reflux.
好了 兄弟们 把头盔带上
O-Okay, guys, just keep your helmets on.
我和无牙仔去找她
Toothless and I will find her.
无牙仔现在已经有了光煞
Toothless has the Light Fury now.
他可能都不会回来了
He's probably not even coming back.
什么？
What?
你给他自由了 小嗝嗝
You gave him his freedom, Hiccup.
你指望什么？
What were you expecting?
我从没想过他永远不回来！
I never thought he'd stay away for good!
我 我…
I-I. …
我会弄明白 我只是需要一点时间
Look, I'll-I'll figure it out. I just need more time.
他觉得他要一个人扛
He thinks he has to lead alone.
因为他父亲是这样
Well, because his father had to.
他没有意识到你们俩的力量
He doesn't realize the strength you have together.
- 你现在还信任他吗？- 当然
- Do you still believe in him? - Of course.
我希望他也信任自己
I wish he did.
但他觉得自己没有无牙仔就一无是处
But he thinks he's nothing without Toothless.
那就帮他认清事实
Then help him realize the truth.
- 上来 - 什么？
- Get on. - What?
我们去找他
We're going to find him.
真的？
Really?
大家留在原地
Everybody, stay put.
我们会把拉芙纳特找回来 别担心
We will get Ruffnut back. Don't worry.
担心？
Worry?
如果他们被拉芙纳特缠上了 我更担心他们呢
If they're stuck with Ruffnut, I'm more worried about them.
为什么你的脸那么长？
Why the long face?
我的脸算长了 但是你的脸才真的长
I mean, mine's long, but yours is really long.
头上没脑子 只剩脸 仿佛出生时被拉长了一样
All face and no brain, like you got stretched at birth.
你是不是也有个双胞胎？
Do you have a twin, too?
特夫纳特把妈妈肚子里的空间都占了
Tuffnut took up all the room in Mom's belly.
否则我的脸就会更圆 也有更多脑髓
Otherwise I'd have a rounder head and more brains.
那是科学
That's science.
我的辫子就像小双头龙 看到没？
My braids are like little Zipplebacks. See?
上面的霉点看着像眼睛 真可爱
Even the mold spots look like eyes. It's so cute.
他们甚至还有小角 什么都有
They even have little horns and everything,
就像巴夫和贝尔奇
just like Barf and Belch.
但是我和巴夫受不了贝尔奇
Except me and Barf can't stand Belch,
所以他们其实就是巴夫
so they're really just Barfs.
这里真热
It's warm in here.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
你从没见过我这么性感的囚犯
You've never had a prisoner this hot.
所有男孩都爱我
All the boys love me.
除了埃雷以外 他完全没机会了
Except Eret, who totally lost his chance.
小伙 船已启航啦 对不起啦
That ship has sailed, boy. Sorry.
而小嗝嗝呢
And Hiccup is practically married.
几乎已经和那个圆脑袋亚丝翠结婚了
to that round-head, Astrid.
但是鼻涕虫和鱼脚司 他们基本就算我的后宫了
But Snotlout and Fishlegs, they're basically my harem.
真是没法选 知道吗？
I just can't choose, you know?
鼻涕虫很健壮 但是长得太帅了 知道吧？
Snotlout's a beefcake but almost too pretty, you know?
有时候我觉得他更爱他自己
Sometimes I think he's more in love with himself than me.
在恋爱中 只容得下一个好看的
There's only room for one beauty in this relationship.
如果困在冰川 我非得吃一个的话
Fishlegs would keep me alive longer if I had to.
鱼脚司可以让我活更久一些
eat one of them, stranded on some glacier somewhere.
但他张口就是龙
But he never shuts up about dragons.
别人不停说话的时候 你会不会讨厌呢？
Don't you hate when people never stop talking?
- 没错 很讨厌 - 他们不停地说啊说
- Yes, I do. - They just keep going and going.
满嘴废话 无聊透了
Blah, blah, blah. It's so boring.
- 我们不能直接把她喂龙吃吗？- 我饿了
- Can't we just feed her to your dragons? - I'm hungry.
嘿 你有什么吃的吗？
Hey, what do you have to eat around here?
和你说一下 我对鱼过敏
I'm allergic to fish. You should know that.
在那个新的蠢岛上 除了鱼什么都没有
That's all they have at that stupid new island.
你有没有蛤可以吃？
Do you have any clams?
它们就像小嘴巴 里面有黏黏的食物
They're like little mouths with slimy food inside.
食物都被咀嚼过了 就像我妈的做法一样
that's already chewed, like the way Mom used to do it.
够了！
Enough!
到了12岁 我妈就说 「该自己嚼食物啦」
Until I turned 12 and she was like, "Chew your own food."
我说 「才不要 我就喜欢这样」
And I was like, "No, I kinda like it."
从没见过这么烦人的玩意
Most annoying creature ever to cross my path.
啊哦 你把龙放出来啦
Oops, you let the dragons out.
我来抓你啦 我来抓你啦
I'm gonna get you. I'm gonna get you.
- 不对 这只来抓你 - 快…
- No, this one's gonna get you. - Get…
带他走！
Take him and go!
拜托了！我求你啦！
Please! I beg you!
毒钳只能少一顿晚餐了
The Deathgrippers will have to forgo dinner.
恶心 你把龙拿去喂龙吃？
Ew, you feed your dragons dragons?
- 走！- 你厕所在哪？
- Go! - Where's your bathroom?
我要…
I got to…
好啦！天啊
Okay! Gods.
难怪你头发都灰了
No wonder you have gray hair.
压力太大对你可不好
Stress is not good for you.
拜拜啦 失败者！
So long, losers!
- 她要去哪里啊？- 她在跟踪什么
- Where，where is she heading? - She's tracking something.
对吧 乖乖？
Aren't you, girl?
什么也没有 只有数英里的…
There's nothing but miles and miles of…
一个巨型瀑布
A great waterfall.
在世界尽头
At the end of the world.
风里飞啊！
Stormfly!
看
Look.
它真的存在
It really does exist.
- 无牙仔 - 嘘 你会吓到他们的
- Toothless. - Shh. You'll spook them.
那才是真王
Now, that's a king.
我们该走了
We should go.
不要
Oh, no.
风里飞啊！
Stormfly!
走！走啊！
Go! Go!
我 对不起 伙计 我 我只是…
I-I'm sorry, bud. I-I just…
儿子
Son.
你应该在睡觉啊
You should be asleep.
我口渴了
I was thirsty.
嗯 过来吧
Yeah, come here.
爸爸？
Dad?
你会给我们找个新妈妈吗？
Are you gonna get us a new mom?
我不想找
I don't want another.
你妈妈是我唯一的女人
Your mom was the only woman for me.
她是我一生的挚爱
She was the love of my life.
但是 有爱就有失去 儿子
But with love comes loss, son.
就是这样
It's part of the deal.
有时会疼 但最终 这都是值得的
Sometimes it hurts, but in the end, it's all worth it.
爱是最伟大的礼物
There's no greater gift than love.
伙计 没关系
It's okay, bud.
你属于那里 和她在一起
You belong there, with her.
我们不属于那里
We don't.
没关系
And that's all right.
我们会想办法去…
We'll find a way to man…
嘿！
Hey!
她跟我们回来了！
She followed us back!
也许我们不用告别呢
We might not have to say good-bye after all.
太好了
That's it.
呜呼！耶！
Woo-hoo! Yeah!
- 拉芙纳特？- 想我了吗？
- Ruffnut? - Miss me?
你逃出来了？
How did you escape?
他们被我烦死了 结果只好放我走
I annoyed them till they let me go.
等等 等等
Wait. Wait.
- 葛林魔让你走了？- 太蠢了
- Grimmel let you go? - So dumb.
他们受不了我了
They couldn't handle me.
看吧 每个人都觉得特夫纳特更烦人 但是…
See, everyone thinks Tuffnut's more annoying, but…
- 等等 等一下 - 拉芙纳特 专心点
- Wait, hold on. - Ruffnut, focus.
有人跟踪你吗？
Were you followed?
我可从不回头 小嗝嗝
I never look back, Hiccup.
无牙仔
Toothless.
无牙仔！
Toothless!
无牙仔 回来！
Toothless, come back!
不要！
No!
我们的小游戏必须结束啦
And now our little game must come to an end.
让它们停下 头龙！
Call them off, alpha!
没必要让她也死吧
No reason for her to die, too.
他们在干嘛？
What are they doing?
- 他们完全可以搞定他的 - 她现在命悬一线
- They could totally take him. - Not with her life on the line.
别费劲了
Save your breath.
现在我才是他们的头龙
The only alpha they respond to is me.
别太难过 你尽力了
don't feel too badly. You tried your best.
但是没有龙 你一无是处
But you are nothing without your dragon.
无牙仔！
Toothless!
噢 这下好了！
Oh, that is just great!
现在怎么办？
Now what?
我觉得该让老二当老大了
I think it's time for number two to become number one.
他会听你的
He'll listen to you.
- 别说了 - 我没这打算
- Don't say it. - I wasn't going to.
我不该把你拉到那里
I shouldn't have dragged you out there.
他就不会送我回来 她就不会跟着了
He wouldn't have flown me back. She wouldn't have followed.
没错
Yep.
现在我就和遇见无牙仔时一样 一团糟
I feel like the same screwup I was before I met Toothless.
嗯 我看得出来
I can see that.
你就打算站在那 同意我说的话吗？
Are you just gonna stand there and agree with everything?
你没错
Well, you're right.
你回到了原点
You're back to where you started,
但我是第一个相信你的人
but I was the first to believe in you.
我一直都看着你
And I have watched you doubt.
怀疑自己是否值得相信
whether you're worthy ever since.
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
因为你 我才成了现在的自己
I am the person I am today because of you.
我从来没告诉你 但这是真的
I never told you that, but it's true.
你是我见过的最勇敢 最固执
You are the bravest, most stubborn,
最坚定的傻瓜
most determined knucklehead I know.
小嗝嗝 这不是无牙仔给你的
Toothless didn't give you that, Hiccup.
- 他只是让它变得… - 更容易
- He just made it… - Easier.
而现在 会难得多
And now it's gonna be a lot harder.
那你打算怎么做？
So, what are you gonna do about it?
很可能做些傻事
Probably something stupid.
这才是我认识的小嗝嗝
That's the Hiccup I know.
大伙 穿上装备 我们去把他们找回来
Suit up, gang. We're going to get them back.
- 什么？- 他疯了
- What? - He's lost his mind.
现在 才像是结婚的料子
Now, that's marriage material.
终于 忠诚的学生 你准备好了
At last, faithful pupil, you are ready.
嗯 没有龙 我们怎么把龙救出来？
Um, how are we gonna get our dragons back without dragons?
相信我
Trust me.
- 当心 - 下一个是你
- Watch yourselves. - You're next.
进去
Move it.
嗯 头龙 做得好
Um, that's right, alpha.
别制造惊喜
No surprises.
穿着这些跳下悬崖
So, jump off the cliff in these.
这就是你最好的打算？
That's the best you've got?
不 你们才是我最好的打算
No, you guys are the best I've got.
- 我支持他！还有谁？- 我支持…
- I'm with him! Who else? - I'm with…
拉芙纳特 那是我的台词
Ruffnut, that was my line.
- 走吧！- 大家跟上！
- Let's go! - Try to keep up!
- 我也来了！- 真棒！
- I'm doing it! - All right!
让开！
Get clear!
你们不会以为我真会把夜煞交给你们吧
You didn't think I'd actually hand you the Night Fury,
是吗？
did you?
他必须死在我手上
He's mine to kill.
那个狡猾的家伙！
That snake!
我要把我的使命完成
I intend to finish what I started.
在没有头龙的情况下想要控制住其他龙 你们就自求多福吧
Best of luck controlling them without an alpha.
坚持住 无牙仔！
Hold on, Toothless!
冲啊！
Let go!
我们应该事先训练一下的！
Could've used some practice!
啊 我不该吃早饭的！
Ah, I should've skipped breakfast!
无牙仔！
Toothless!
小心！
Look out!
好烫 好烫！
Hot, hot, hot, hot!
龙都逃出来了！
They're getting away!
时机完美
Perfect timing.
- 放下武器！- 我来解决那个皮包骨头！
- Put that down! - I'll take the skinny one!
认真起来吧！
Game faces!
你们还在等什么？上啊
Yeah, what are you waiting for? Get in there.
吃我一招！
Take that!
- 小心！- 四处都是龙啊！
- Watch out! - The dragons are everywhere!
- 他们来啦！- 他们来啦！
- Incoming! - Here they come!
前方有攻击！
Incoming!
快躲起来！
Take cover!
你要去哪儿？！
Where are you going?!
- 注意！- 谢了
- Heads up! - Thanks.
小心！
Look out!
谢了
Thanks.
我来了 无牙仔！
I'm coming, Toothless!
你觉得他还在乎你吗？
You still think he cares about you?
就让我们看看他到底会选谁
Let's just see who he follows.
老兄 发生了这一切我很抱歉
I'm sorry, bud, for everything.
好了 我们去把她找回来
Now, let's go get her.
二当家冲锋陷阵！
Number two coming through!
意不意外！
Surprise!
真是抱歉了
Sorry about that.
冲啊
Come on.
- 很好！- 又放出一只！还有四只
- All right! - One more free! Four to go!
跟上我！
Try to keep up!
我会护着你的 哦！
I got your backs. Oh!
不错嘛 我们简直像一个团队
Yeah, it's almost like we're a team.
你居然让一只龙宝宝上战场
You brought a baby to a battle.
如果是你 我绝对不会这么做
Ah-ah-ah. I wouldn't do that if I were you.
天啊 我好喜欢那条龙啊
God, I love that dragon.
上啊！快回来！
Come on! Come back here!
我们这么晚才出场 真是抱歉啦
Sorry we're late for the party.
你们来得正是时候
You're right on time.
它来了 它来了
That's it. That's it.
我们怎么才能把他从她背上轰下去 而又不伤害她呢？
How are we gonna get him off her back without hurting her?
为我的毛发瑟瑟发抖吧！
Fear the facial hair!
- 我真是想念战场 - 我也是
- Oh, I have missed this. - Me, too.
看到他了吗？
Ooh. See that there?
好可爱
Aw. Cute.
这是个坏兆头 你被诅咒了
That's a bad omen. You're cursed.
就是这样 上啊！
Yes! Go on!
好样的！
Good on you!
我现在觉得你也没那么坏了
I guess you're not so bad after all.
弃船！
Abandon ship!
棒极了！
Oh, that was awesome!
我们碰上麻烦了
Uh, we've got problems.
拿下他 小嗝嗝！
Take him down, Hiccup!
我们得尽快想到一个更好的计划
We need a better plan, and quick!
你 你在干嘛？
Uh, uh, what are, what are you doing?
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
他去哪儿了？
Where has he gone?
你会让我们俩同归于尽的！
You'll kill both of us!
为一条龙而战？
Fighting over a dragon?
这就是你的计划？
That's your plan?
没错
This is.
去救他
Save him.
不要！
No!
看吧
See?
我就知道你会来
I knew you'd come around.
老兄 早上好啊
Hey. Good morning, bud.
你醒啦
Here you go.
你总是能给我们惊喜
Boy, you're full of surprises.
他是你的
He's all yours.
埃雷可能是有过人的体魄
You know, Eret may be blessed with brawn,
不过别告诉别人 你的谋略胜于他
but, just between us, you have the brains.
我是老大
Number one.
你是对的 老兄 时候到了
You're right, bud. It's time.
一直以来 我都在为自己追寻的世界而战斗
I was so busy fighting for a world that I wanted,
却从没想过你到底需要什么
I didn't think about what you needed.
你照顾我们够久了
You've looked after us for long enough.
是时候为你自己着想了
Time to look after yourselves.
哦 风里飞 我的好姑娘
Oh, Stormfly, my good girl.
好吧 格拉姆
All right, Grumpy.
你走吧
Off you go.
你陪我已经这么久了 丑大个
So long, you big ugly beast.
我会想你的
I'll miss you.
哦 云中跃 哦
Oh, Cloudjumper. Oh.
去吧 老兄
Go on, bud.
把他们带向隐秘之地
Lead them to the Hidden World.
在那里你们会很安全
You'll be safe there.
比你和我在一起时安全得多
Safer than you could ever be with me.
没事的 我也爱你
It's okay. I love you, too.
而且我希望你能得到自由
And I want you to be free.
我们的世界还不值得你停留
Our world doesn't deserve you.
就目前而言
Yet.
走吧 无牙仔
Go, Toothless.
走吧
Go.
让我们祝福酋长和酋长夫人！
To the chief and chieftess!
祝你们幸福！
Good on you!
来吧 把头埋在我浓密的胡子上哭泣吧
Come, cry into my full, thick beard.
太美了！
It's so beautiful!
真恶心
Gross.
好吧 算你赢了
Okay, you win.
我喜欢多愁善感的男人
I like sensitive guys.
我还以为这一天永远不会到来呢
I thought it would never happen.
有生之年 是吧？
Finally, right?
当我还是个小孩的时候 我身边有很多龙
There were dragons when I was a boy.
他们当中有美丽威严 在天空中飞的龙
Ah, there were great, grim sky dragons.
像可怕的巨鸟一样 栖息在悬崖顶部
that nested on the clifftops like gigantic, scary birds.
也有小小的 棕色的 在地上跑的龙
Little, brown, scuttling dragons.
他们成群结队 消灭地上的老鼠
that hunted down the mice and rats in well-organized packs.
还有大得惊人的海龙
Preposterously huge sea dragons.
他们有蓝鲸的20倍大
that were 20 times as big as the big blue whale.
有人说他们潜回海中
Some say they crawled back into the sea,
没有留下骨头 毒牙 让人寻不到他们存在的痕迹
leaving not a bone nor a fang for men to remember them by.
还有人说 他们不过就是一些民间故事
Others say they were nothing but folktales to begin with.
我接受这种说法
Ah, I'm okay with that.
嘿 老兄
Hey there, bud.
还记得我吗？
Remember me?
没事的
It's okay.
嘿 老兄 我也很高兴见到你
Hey, I am glad to see you, too, bud.
他不会吃掉你们爸爸的
He's not gonna eat your father.
你的尾巴怎么样了？
How's the tail holding up?
可能需要加点油 调整一下
Probably could use some oil and a little fine-tuning.
看吧 没事的 他们是朋友
Look, it's okay. They're friends.
行啦行啦
Cut it out.
过来
Here.
去吧 没事的
Go on. It's all right.
过来
Come.
他不会伤害你们的
He won't hurt you.
把你们的手伸出来
Hold your hands out.
像这样
Like this.
对了
That's it.
让他靠近你们
Let him come to you.
传闻说
Legend says that.
当大地震动 或者岩浆从地表漫出的时候
when the ground quakes or lava spews from the earth,
那是龙为了让我们知道他们的存在
it's the dragons, letting us know they're still here,
等着我们可以和他们和平共处
waiting for us to figure out how to get along.
是的 世间众人都认为就算龙真实存在过
Yes, the world believes the dragons are gone,
也已经消失了
if they ever existed at all.
但我们维京人知道事实不是这样
But we Berkians, we know otherwise.
我们会一直守候这个秘密
And we'll guard this secret until the time comes.
直到龙可以和平归来的那一刻
when dragons can return in peace.
《驯龙高手3：隐秘的世界》
∮ 我和你 我们经历了一切 ∮
∮ You and I, we've been through it all ∮
∮ 现在是时候说再见了吗？∮
∮ Is it time to say good-bye? ∮
∮ 擦干你的眼泪 ∮
∮ Dry your eye ∮
∮ 我们在彼此身旁 ∮
∮ We have been together ∮
∮ 已经这么久了 ∮
∮ So long ∮
∮ 现在是时候放手了吗？∮
∮ Is it time to let go? ∮
∮ 我们天各一方 ∮
∮ Apart we grow ∮
∮ 很快我们就会知道 ∮
∮ Soon we will know ∮
∮ 你是我继续生活下去的理由 ∮
∮ You are the reason to go on living ∮
∮ 我会不断尝试新事物 一切全靠我自己 ∮
∮ I need to try things and be on my own ∮
∮ 我们会是永远的朋友 ∮
∮ We'll always be friends ∮
∮ 我们会保持一定距离 ∮
∮ We'll keep our distance ∮
∮ 但即使天各一方 我们的心永远都在一起 ∮
∮ We'll be together from afar forever ∮
∮ 你听 你听 ∮
∮ Listen, listen ∮
∮ 用心听… ∮
∮ Within, ooh-ooh… ∮
∮ 我们走过世界每个角落 ∮
∮ We have been, we've been everywhere ∮
∮ 曾至星空又复返 ∮
∮ To the stars and back again ∮
∮ 是的 我的朋友 ∮
∮ Yes, my friend ∮
∮ 我们见识过大千世界 ∮
∮ We have seen, we've seen everything ∮
∮ 可我还能再见到你吗 ∮
∮ But will I ever see you again ∮
∮ 我的老朋友？∮
∮ My old friend? ∮
∮ 一直到最后我们都是朋友… ∮
∮ Friends till the end… ∮
∮ 你是我 ∮
∮ You are the reason ∮
∮ 继续生活下去的理由 ∮
∮ To go on living ∮
∮ 我会不断尝试新事物 一切全靠我自己 ∮
∮ I need to try things and be on my own ∮
∮ 我们会是永远的朋友 ∮
∮ We'll always be friends ∮
∮ 我们会保持一定距离 ∮
∮ We'll keep our distance ∮
∮ 但即使天各一方 我们的心永远都在一起 ∮
∮ We'll be together from afar forever ∮
∮ 你听 你听 用心听 ∮
∮ Listen, listen, within ∮
∮ 你和我 我们要说再见了 ∮
∮ You and I, we say our good-byes ∮
∮ 什么时候才能再见到你呢？∮
∮ When will I see you again? ∮
∮ 你和我 我们要说再见了 ∮
∮ You and I, we say our good-byes ∮
∮ 什么时候才能再见到你呢？∮
∮ When will I see you again? ∮
∮ 你和我 我们要说再见了 ∮
∮ You and I, we say our good-byes ∮
∮ 什么时候才能再见到你呢？∮
∮ When will I see you again? ∮
∮ 你和我 我们要说再见了 ∮
∮ You and I, we say our good-byes ∮
∮ 什么时候才能再见到你呢？∮
∮ When will I see you again? ∮